Hello.
The next technique we're going to cover is simply correcting.
It's how to make up for those little mistakes or, when your painting doesn't quite go in the direction you imagined it should go in.
Take, for example this area here.
Let's say the blue looks really, really great but you know what?
I 'd want this to be a lot more red up here and I don't, if I blend the red in here it's going to look like a milky-bluish red purple and it's not what I want to do.
What do I do?
How do I fix this?
Mr. Paper Towel or Mr.
Paint Rag is going to be your best friend.
Especially if working oils, oftentimes you'll have hours to days to fix this.
If you're working on acrylics, your window is down to minutes.
They are so fast drying.
Take your towel, basically very simply wipe the paint away.
Be thorough with this, keep wiping until basically, very little paint is coming off on your paper towel.
If your paper towel is saturated, get another one.
Don't stop just because you ran out of paper towels.
Now your canvas is relatively pure again.
It's not going to be exactly how a bare canvas is, but it's going to be good enough for you to start coming back in here with your red.
I'm going to come back in here and blend her up over the blue however you like it, now the blue is a lot more subdued.
You have a red here, and all because you took the time, basically to wipe it away and repaint.
That is the biggest thing.
Don't ever think of a painting as a static thing.
I've even seen paintings entirely dry where an artist goes 'no, I'm not happy' and they'll paint even over the dry under painting completely.